<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business on yogeshsn</title>
    <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/categories/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business on yogeshsn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 19:38:01 +0545</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="www.yogeshsn.com.np/categories/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Strategic Leadership</title>
      <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/posts/day1_10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 19:38:01 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.yogeshsn.com.np/posts/day1_10/</guid>
      
      <description>Strategic Leadership in the 21st Century: Navigating the Complexities of Business Introduction Welcome to the prestigious MBA program at Harvard University, where we embark on a transformative journey to cultivate strategic leaders equipped to navigate the dynamic landscape of the 21st-century business world. In this article, we will delve into key aspects of strategic leadership, supported by real-life case studies and demonstrations, aiming to empower you with the knowledge and skills essential for success.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pricing Strategies</title>
      <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/posts/day1_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 19:05:30 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.yogeshsn.com.np/posts/day1_9/</guid>
      
      <description>10. Pricing Strategies: Finding the Right Value for Your Services Determining the right pricing for your services is a critical aspect of business success. Here are key insights and strategies to help you establish a pricing model that reflects the true value of your offerings.
1. Know Your Worth:
Assess the value of your services and charge accordingly. Avoid undervaluing your expertise or lowering prices in the hope of future work.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sales Cycle</title>
      <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/posts/day1_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 19:05:23 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.yogeshsn.com.np/posts/day1_8/</guid>
      
      <description>Sales Cycle: Navigating the Path to Revenue Understanding the sales cycle is essential for businesses aiming to convert leads into customers and generate revenue. Let&amp;rsquo;s map out the process of earning money from a customer&amp;rsquo;s pocket, explore the time frame, and discuss strategies for managing expenses until there is payback.
1. Sales Cycle Mapping: Earning Money from Customer&amp;rsquo;s Pocket A. Lead Generation:
Identify and attract potential customers through marketing efforts, including content marketing, advertising, and social media.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Acquisition</title>
      <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/posts/day1_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 19:05:17 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.yogeshsn.com.np/posts/day1_7/</guid>
      
      <description>8. Customer Acquisition: Strategies for Success Acquiring customers is a crucial aspect of business growth, and it requires strategic planning and effective networking. Here are key insights and strategies to ensure successful customer acquisition:
1. Focus on Value Over Volume: Rather than targeting a broad audience, focus on reaching those who truly value your products or services. Remember that you are paid for the value you provide, not just your time.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Branding</title>
      <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/posts/day1_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 19:05:13 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.yogeshsn.com.np/posts/day1_6/</guid>
      
      <description>7. Persona Development and Branding: Crafting an Authentic Online Presence In the digital age, establishing a strong online presence is vital for personal and business success. Persona development and branding play pivotal roles in shaping how you are perceived in the virtual world. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore the steps to create an impactful website and portfolio, connect with social media, and make a meaningful promotion that resonates with your audience.
Persona Development: Understanding Your Identity Define Your Persona:</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decision Making</title>
      <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/posts/day1_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 19:02:42 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.yogeshsn.com.np/posts/day1_5/</guid>
      
      <description>6. Decision Making Unit: Understanding the Dynamics In the business landscape, understanding the decision-making unit (DMU) is crucial. The DMU comprises individuals and entities that influence the purchase decision. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore this concept and its significance, along with insights into product development and customer engagement.
Decision Making Unit: Identifying Key Players Primary Decision-Maker:
Who has the authority to make the final decision? What criteria influence their choices? Influencers:
What external factors influence the decision?</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pilot Market</title>
      <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/posts/day1_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 19:02:37 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.yogeshsn.com.np/posts/day1_4/</guid>
      
      <description>5. Focused Pilot Market: Case Studies and Key Questions Let&amp;rsquo;s delve into case studies that highlight the importance of a focused pilot market strategy and explore the key questions to identify the suitability of your chosen market segment.
Case Study 1: Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Strategic Evolution Amazon, founded by Jeff Bezos, began its journey as an online bookstore. The focused pilot market strategy allowed Amazon to test its business model, build customer trust, and optimize its logistics.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Market Segmentation</title>
      <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/posts/day1_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 19:00:47 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.yogeshsn.com.np/posts/day1_3/</guid>
      
      <description>4. Market Segmentation: Crafting Success Through Customer-Centric Strategies Understanding your target market is fundamental to any successful business venture. Market segmentation involves breaking down a broad market into smaller, more manageable segments based on various criteria. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore the key components of effective market segmentation and how you can leverage it to benefit both your customers and your business.
A. Look Through the Customer&amp;rsquo;s Eyes: Understanding Perspectives Viewing the market from the customer&amp;rsquo;s perspective is crucial.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Priority Management</title>
      <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/posts/day1_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 18:59:35 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.yogeshsn.com.np/posts/day1_2/</guid>
      
      <description>2. Office Setup: Creating Your Productive Work Environment Setting up an effective office space is crucial for entrepreneurs and freelancers. Your work environment can significantly impact your productivity and overall well-being. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore the key steps to establish an office that fosters creativity and efficiency.
A. Hire a Room or House: Tailor Your Environment to Your Needs Consider your budget and explore options for hiring a dedicated room or house to serve as your workspace.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freelancing </title>
      <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/posts/day1_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 18:56:39 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.yogeshsn.com.np/posts/day1_1/</guid>
      
      <description>Embarking on the Entrepreneurial Journey: Navigating Loneliness and Embracing Challenges Starting a business is a transformative journey filled with challenges, loneliness, and the constant scrutiny of others. However, it is also a path that can lead to immense personal and professional growth. In this guide, we will explore the initial steps of starting a business, focusing on the early stages of freelancing and skill development.
1. Freelancing: The First Form of Startup Embarking on the entrepreneurial journey often starts with freelancing.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
