<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tracking my days... on yogeshsn</title>
    <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/discipline/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tracking my days... on yogeshsn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/discipline/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 2- January 2024</title>
      <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/discipline/week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 21:40:28 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/discipline/week2/</guid>
      
      <description>Week 2 Summary - January 2024 Highlights: Two-day training in the Water-Energy-Food-Ecosystem (WEFE) Nexus Pilot Academic Course. Insight gained on the necessity of deploying tools and engineering for meeting Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs). Physical Activities: Ran over 18 km. Completed 300 pushups, squats, sit-ups, and other exercises. Meditated for 20 minutes each day for 6 days. Enjoyed a 5+ hour hike on Friday to reconnect with nature. Productivity: Published an article on the Grand Ethiopian Renaissance Dam (GERD).</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1- January 2024</title>
      <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/discipline/week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 08:43:28 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/discipline/week1/</guid>
      
      <description>Monthly Plan for January 2024 This week is about to end. Today is January 6, 2024. I posted a message on January 1st highlighting the need for good planning, dedication, and hard work. In the final lines, I made a commitment to follow up with posts that would underscore my plans and activity lists, focusing on my dreams.
For this reason, I&amp;rsquo;ve come up with a subtle plan for this month, which aims to yield benefits in five major areas: Physical Wellbeing, Mental Toughness, Spiritual Understanding, Social Connection, and Career Orientation.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
