<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chinese on yogeshsn</title>
    <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/categories/chinese/</link>
    <description>Recent content in chinese on yogeshsn</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 07:33:46 +0545</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="www.yogeshsn.com.np/categories/chinese/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learn Basic Chinese - 12</title>
      <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_speaking12/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 07:33:46 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_speaking12/</guid>
      
      <description>Chinese Language Tutorial - Part 12 时不我待 (Shí bù wǒ dài)
Time waits for no one. Dialogue:
A: 现在几点？ (Xiànzài jǐ diǎn?) B: 现在十二点一刻。 (Xiànzài shí&amp;rsquo;èr diǎn yí kè.) New Words:
Pinyin Character English Translation wèn 问 to ask Xiǎomíng 小明 name of person huídá 回答 to answer Examples:
有问题吗？ (Yǒu wèntí ma?) - Do you have any questions? 办公楼在教学楼北边 (Bàngōng lóu zài jiàoxué lóu běibian) - The teaching building is next to the Administrative building.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Basic Chinese - 11</title>
      <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_speaking11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 11:37:52 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_speaking11/</guid>
      
      <description>Chinese Language Tutorial: Part 11 Vocabulary New Words xiànzài (n.) - now diǎn (mw.) - o’clock kè (mw.) - quarter bàn (num.) - half zǎofàn (n.) - breakfast shíhòu (n.) - time shàngkè (v.) - to attend class Revision cóng&amp;hellip; dào&amp;hellip; - from&amp;hellip; to&amp;hellip; shàngwǔ - morning jīntiān - today yuè - month hào (rì) - date xīngqī - week xīngqīrì - Sunday Phrases tīng xiě - dictation ba - suggestion or confirmation zánmen - we; us a - tail of spoken particle chūfā - depart; to set out xíng - OK; capable jiànmiàn - to meet chà - to be less than Dialogue Asking About Time Xiǎoyè: Xiànzài jǐ diǎn?</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Basic Chinese - 10</title>
      <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_speaking10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 11:36:28 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_speaking10/</guid>
      
      <description>Chinese Language Tutorial - Part 10: Vocabulary Pinyin Character Meaning fùqīn 父亲 father gōngzuò 工作 to work; work, job yīshēng 医生 doctor mǔqīn 母亲 mother gōngsī 公司 company zhíyuán 职员 staff member jìzhě 记者 journalist fùmǔ 父母 parents jīnnián 今年 this year duō 多 to what extent (Question) niánjì 年纪 age suì 岁 year (of age) mìmì 秘密 secret; confidential háizi 孩子 child érzi 儿子 son zhēn 真 really, very shòuhuòyuán 售货员 shop assistant jīnglǐ 经理 manager sījī 司机 driver yéye 爷爷 grandfather nǎinai 奶奶 grandmother dàngāo 蛋糕 cake míngpiàn 名片 name card jìtā 记它 to remember xǐhuan 喜欢 to like ài 爱 to love dà gē 大哥 elder brother (respectful) dà jiě 大姐 elder sister (respectful) Asking about Profession (Be careful!</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese Vocabulary</title>
      <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_vocabulary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 08:52:35 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_vocabulary/</guid>
      
      <description>Chinese Vocabulary Pinyin Character Meaning nǐ 你 you hǎo 好 good; well wǒ 我 I; me shì 是 to be; is bù 不 not shénme 什么 what míngzi 名字 name jiào 叫 to be called hāo 号 number nǎ 哪 which guó 国 country zhōngguó 中国 China rén 人 person jīntiān 今天 today zuótiān 昨天 yesterday míngtiān 明天 tomorrow wǎnshàng 晚上 evening zǎoshang 早上 morning xiàwǔ 下午 afternoon shàngwǔ 上午 before noon xiànsheng 先生 Mr.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Basic Chinese - 9</title>
      <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_speaking9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 07:49:22 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_speaking9/</guid>
      
      <description>Chinese Language Tutorial - Part 9: Dialogue 1: Text:
Sūn lǎoshī: Nǐ xuéxí shénme?
Luó shān: Wǒ xuéxí hànyǔ.
Sūn lǎoshī: Nǐ zài nǎr xuéxí hànyǔ?
Luó shān: Wǒ zài zhōngguó wénhuà zhōngxīn xuéxí hànyǔ.
Sūn lǎoshī: Nǐmen bān yǒu duōshao xuéshēng?
Luó shān: Wǒmen bān yǒu sānshí gè xuéshēng.
Sūn lǎoshī: Jǐ wèi lǎoshī jiào nǐmen?
Luó shān: Sān wèi lǎoshī jiāo wǒmen.
Dialogue 1: Teacher: What are you studying?</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Basic Chinese - 8</title>
      <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_speaking8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 07:49:17 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_speaking8/</guid>
      
      <description>Chinese Language Tutorial - Part 8 Nǐ shì nǎ guó rén? Which country are you from? New words:
Pronunciation Meaning nǎ pron. which guó n. country jiào v. to call míngzi n. name guìxìng n. asking surname (politely) guì adj. expensive; honorable xìng v./n. to surname; surname jǐ wèi lǎoshī jiāo nǐmen? How many teachers teach you? New words:
Pronunciation Meaning jǐ how many wèi for respected person jiāo v. to teach zhù v.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Basic Chinese - 7</title>
      <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_speaking7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 07:49:13 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_speaking7/</guid>
      
      <description>Chinese Language Tutorial - Part 7 Health and Study Conversation Dialogue:
Zhōngguó péngyǒu: Zuìjìn nǐ shēntǐ hǎo ma? (How is your health?) Lì lì: Wǒ shēntǐ hěn hǎo. (My health is very good.) Zhōngguó péngyǒu: Nǐ xuéxí máng ma? (Are you busy with studies?) Lì lì: Wǒ xuéxí bǐjiào máng. (I am relatively busy with studies.) Zhōngguó péngyǒu: Nǐ chéngjì hǎo ma? (How are your grades?) Lì lì: Mǎmahūhū. (So-so.) Zhōngguó péngyǒu: Nǐmen bān tóngxué xuéxí nǔlì ma?</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Basic Chinese - 6</title>
      <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_speaking6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 20:00:58 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_speaking6/</guid>
      
      <description>Chinese Language Tutorial - Part 6 Word Order in a Chinese Sentence A Chinese sentence typically follows the subject-predicate structure, where the subject, often a noun or pronoun, precedes the predicate, typically a verb or adjective. For example:
Sub + Predicate: tā shì lǎoshī. pǔruì shi liúxuéshēng. tā hěn piàoliang. Sentence Making Use the given words to create sentences:
zhè bǐ shì ____________ (This pen is ____________.) shū xīn hěn ____________ (The book is _____________.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Basic Chinese - 5</title>
      <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_speaking5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 20:00:53 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_speaking5/</guid>
      
      <description>Chinese Language Tutorial - Part 5 New Words Verbs qù (去) - to go rènshi (认识) - to meet; to know xuéxí (学习) - to learn; to study Adjectives gāoxìng (高兴) - happy Pronouns zhè (这) - this nà (那) - that Particles de (的) - of yíxiàr (一下) - casual action (once) Nouns hànyǔ (汉语) - Chinese Language bān (班) - class kǒuyǔ (口语) - Spoken Language xuésheng (学生) - student Níbó’ěr (尼泊尔) - Nepal rén (人) - people zhè (这) - this nà (那) - that péngyou (朋友) - friend Jiādémǎndū (加德满都) - Kathmandu Bókǎlā (博卡拉) - Pokhara Lán pí ní (兰比尼) - Lumbini Proper Nouns Pǔruì (普瑞) - Pradeep Luóshān (罗山) - Roshan Lìlì (丽丽) - Sonali Additional Words hé (和) - and; with jiàoshì (教室) - classroom dà (大) - big xīn (新) - new tóngxué (同学) - classmate hòu (厚) - thick piàoliang (漂亮) - pretty; beautiful jíle (极了) - extremely nǚ’ér (女儿) - daughter cōngming (聪明) - clever kě’ài (可爱) - lovely kàn (看) - to look shuài (帅) - handsome xiǎo (小) - small, little Conversation A: Qǐngwèn, túshūguǎn zài nǎr?</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Basic Chinese - 4</title>
      <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_speaking4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 20:00:49 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_speaking4/</guid>
      
      <description>Chinese Language Tutorial - Part 4 New Words Vocabulary yào (要) - would like to; want to huàn (换) - to change qián (钱) - money duōshao (多少) - how much, how many bǎi (百) - hundred měiyuán (美元) - US dollar lúbǐ (卢比) - Rupees Measure Words bēi (杯) - cup, glass kuài (yuán) (块/元) - Chinese monetary unit gè (个) - a general measure word máo (jiǎo) (毛/角) - 1/10 of yuan fēn (分) - 1/10 of jiao píng (瓶) - bottle běn (本) - a measure word for books, etc.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Basic Chinese - 3</title>
      <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_speaking3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 20:00:45 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_speaking3/</guid>
      
      <description>Chinese Language Tutorial - Part 3 Food and Drinks Vocabulary chī (吃) - to eat shénme (什么) - what jiǎozi (饺子) - dumpling mǐfàn (米饭) - cooked rice miàntiáo (面条) - noodle miànbāo (面包) - bread bāozi (包子) - steamed stuffed bun Conversation A: 你吃什么？ (Nǐ chī shénme?)
B: 我吃饺子。 (Wǒ chī jiǎozi.)
Drinks Vocabulary hē (喝) - to drink píjiǔ (啤酒) - beer chá (茶) - tea kāfēi (咖啡) - coffee shuǐ (水) - water niúnǎi (牛奶) - milk Kěkǒu-kělè (可口可乐) - Coca-cola Conversation A: 你喝什么？ (Nǐ hē shénme?</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Basic Chinese - 2</title>
      <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_speaking2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 20:00:42 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_speaking2/</guid>
      
      <description>Chinese Language Tutorial - Part 2 New Vocabulary Verbs Qǐng (请) - Please jìn (进) - Enter zuò (坐) - Sit tīng (听) - Listen shuō (说) - Speak dú (读) - Read Interrogative Particle ma (吗) - A question particle Pronouns wǒ (我) - I, me tā (他/她) - He/She tāmen (他们/她们) - They, them Adverbs and Particles hěn (很) - Very ne (呢) - A particle indicating a question yě (也) - Too, also Family Members bàba (爸爸) - Father māma (妈妈) - Mother gēge (哥哥) - Elder brother jiějie (姐姐) - Elder sister dìdi (弟弟) - Younger brother mèimei (妹妹) - Younger sister Tone Positions mā (马) - Ma (first tone) hǎo (好) - Good (third tone) zuò (坐) - Sit (4th tone) mì (米) - Rice (4th tone) jīng (京) - Capital (1st tone) liù (六) - Six (4th tone) guì (贵) - Expensive (4th tone) Conversation A: 你好吗？ (Nǐ hǎo ma?</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Basic Chinese - 1</title>
      <link>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_speaking1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 20:00:37 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.yogeshsn.com.np/references/chinese_speaking/chinese_speaking1/</guid>
      
      <description>Chinese Language Tutorial - Part 1 Tones Chinese is a tonal language, and tones play a crucial role in distinguishing meanings. There are four basic tones:
ā (first tone) á (second tone) ǎ (third tone) à (fourth tone) Tone Drills Practice the tones with the following examples:
mā (马) - horse mà (骂) - scold Why are Tones Important? Tones change the meaning of a word, emphasizing the importance of proper pronunciation.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
